Rodolfo Hans S. Silva

Consolação, São Paulo / He, Him

+55 21 98261-8770 rodolfohans@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/rodolfohans

ABOUT ME

I am a Designer with 13 years of experience across the areas of product, UX, marketing and web design. I bring a diverse skill set to my work and I am passionate about creating great experiences, while achieving a balance between user needs and techinical feasibility.

PORTFOLIO

rodolfohans.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Accenture / UX and UI Designer

October 2019 to March 2023 on multiple projects, including:

Banco PAN / go!PAN Veículos

buyers, reducing time-consuming processes such as credit simulation and validating applications. Together with a user researcher, we conducted tests and interviews to measure results and assist the PO and PMO in defining a better feature roadmap.

I contributed to streamline the vehicle financing simulation platform for sellers and

Our efforts resulted in a significant improvement in the platform's ranking, moving from 4th to 2nd place in small car sales financing. Additionally, we resolved design inconsistencies and aligned the platform with the bank's design system.

BRK Ambiental / Backoffice Proprietary System

I contributed to an ongoing digital decoupling project, where we successfully transformed a legacy backoffice system for water and sewage control into a web-based and mobilefriendly platform powered by independent APIs. Additionally, we had to align it with the customer channel app visual identity.

By proposing and testing new user flows, I improved the platform's architecture, enhancing its information organization. Moreover, I adapted the original style system to better suit the needs of backoffice staff, providing higher density information and specialized elements to optimize their workflows.

Nutrien Soluções Agrícolas / Web Communication Rebranding Execution

I worked at its corp portal, implementing post launch features and addressing its bug backlog. One of the key areas I focused on was refactoring its weather service for small producers, enhancing its functionality and usability.

Furthermore, we expanded the original strategy to encompass the entire Latin American region, unifying the customer experience across Brazil, Argentina, Chile, and Uruguay, wich required constant collaboration with the Argentinian branch and a deeper understanding of each country's unique characteristics and how each one positioned its products and services portfolios.

Key functions across all projects:

- Conduct interviews with firsthand users.
- Gather insights from previous interviews and reports. • Execute usability tests and summarize insights.
- Create and refine workflows.
- Create high-fidelity UI.
- Organize design assets.

Previous experiences: Nexaas / UI Designer

October 2016 to September 2019

May 2016 to October 2016

Agência Wink Mídia / Graphic Designer

Freelancer / Graphic Designer

May 2014 to February 2016

Época Cosméticos / Web Designer March 2012 to May 2014

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Game Artist EBAC / 2023 / Ongoing

Android Developer

Instituto Infnet / 2015 / 128 hours

Bachelor in Video Game Design

Universidade Estácio de Sá / 2014 to 2015 / Discontinued **Bachelor in Industrial Design**

Universidade Estácio de Sá / 2006 to 2011

SKILLS

Proficient in:

- UX discovery methodologies
- UI design and process documentation UI validations

- **Currently studying:**
 - Game mechanics creation and documentation
 - UI design and flow applied to games Concept art design
- 3D modeling

- Others:

 - Image manipulation Vectorial illustration
 - Motion graphics notion

· HTML, CSS and JS notion

Editorial design